[
    {
        "question": "Who was the first wife of Prophet Muhammad (Salallahu Alayhi Walehi Wa Sallam)?",
        "optionA": "Hazrat Ayesha (R.A)",
        "optionB": "Hazrat Jaweria (R.A)",
        "optionC": "Hazrat Khadijah (R.A)",
        "optionD": "Hazrat Umm-E-Habiba (R.A)",
        "answer": "Hazrat Khadijah (R.A)"
    },

     {
        "question": "What is a woman's status in Islam?",
        "optionA": "In Islam, women have only a few basic rights",
        "optionB": "In Islam, a woman's life ends when her husband dies",
        "optionC": "In Islam, women are held in very high esteem",
        "optionD": "All of the above",
        "answer": "In Islam, women are held in very high esteem"
    },

    {
        "question": "One of the way Islam spread at the very beginning was because _______",
        "optionA": "Slaves who were freed by Abu Bakr (r.a.) converted to Islam",
        "optionB": "The non-believers were forced to convert to Islam or be killed",
        "optionC": "The non-believers were offered money to convert to Islam",
        "optionD": "The non-believers were concerned for persecution if not converted to Islam",
        "answer": "Slaves who were freed by Abu Bakr (r.a.) converted to Islam"
    },

    {
        "question": "All people are equal in Islam except on the basis of one thing. What is it?",
        "optionA": "Taqwa (fear of Allah)",
        "optionB": "Physical beauty",
        "optionC": "Ancestry",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "Taqwa (fear of Allah)"
    },

    {
        "question": "Name the Sura that refers to Orphans and Neighbors?",
        "optionA": "Nasr",
        "optionB": "Alaq",
        "optionC": "Maun",
        "optionD": "Zilzal",
        "answer": "Maun"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is Hijra?",
        "optionA": "Prophet Muhammad (Salallahu Alayhi Walehi Wa Sallam) coming back to Makkah from Madinah",
        "optionB": "The migration of the Prophet Muhammad (Salallahu Alayhi Walehi Wa Sallam) from Makkah to Madina",
        "optionC": "Beginning of Islamic calendar",
        "optionD": "The time when people started accepting Islam",
        "answer": "The migration of the Prophet Muhammad (Salallahu Alayhi Walehi Wa Sallam) from Makkah to Madina"
    },

    {
        "question": "When Abu Bakr (r.a.) learned about the death of Prophet (pbuh), he said 'O people! Whoever worshipped Muhammad should know that Muhammad is dead. Whoever worshipped ______________ should know that ________ is alive and will never die.'",
        "optionA": "Me",
        "optionB": "Abu Bakr (r.a.)",
        "optionC": "Allah (SWT)",
        "optionD": "Isa",
        "answer": "Allah (SWT)"
    },

    {
        "question": "What should a Muslim begin his daily life with?",
        "optionA": "with a 30 min.of TV dose",
        "optionB": "with a 5 mile jog",
        "optionC": "with a healthy breakfast",
        "optionD": "with Salat al Fajr",
        "answer": "with Salat al Fajr"
    },

    {
        "question": "According to the Prophet (Salallahu Alayhi Walehi Wa Sallam) 'A powerful human being is one who controls himself when he is .....'",
        "optionA": "Hungry",
        "optionB": "Thirsty",
        "optionC": "Angry",
        "optionD": "Crying and sad",
        "answer": "Angry"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a good Islamic example of Kindness and Gentleness:",
        "optionA": "Avoiding bad language.",
        "optionB": "Controlling one's anger.",
        "optionC": "Speaking loudly so that people other than being addressed can hear you.",
        "optionD": "When and if required to correct people in a polite and gentle manner.",
        "answer": "Speaking loudly so that people other than being addressed can hear you."
    },

    {
        "question": "In verse 7 of Sura Bayyinah, the first part of the Ayah says 'Those who ) have faith and do righteous deeds' .. what's the second part of this Ayah?",
        "optionA": "they are the best of creatures",
        "optionB": "are upright people",
        "optionC": "are the people of the book",
        "optionD": "none of the above",
        "answer": "they are the best of creatures"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the manners of reading the Quran:",
        "optionA": "Gathering in a group to read and study the Quran is recommended.",
        "optionB": "Frequent reading of the Quran is recommended so that one can fully understand the Quran.",
        "optionC": "The Quran is meant to be recited to aquire the knowledge of Allah(SWT)",
        "optionD": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },

    {
        "question": "The Arabic word 'Iman' means:",
        "optionA": "To acknowledge",
        "optionB": "To understand",
        "optionC": "To believe",
        "optionD": "B & C",
        "answer": "To believe"
    },

    {
        "question": "What do we have to have from among the following, in order to be obedient to Allah and live a life according to His laws?",
        "optionA": "faith in the unknown and unseen",
        "optionB": "knowledge of the unknown and faith in the known",
        "optionC": "faith in the unseen and knowledge of the unknown",
        "optionD": "all of the above",
        "answer": "faith in the unknown and unseen"
    },

    {
        "question": "How many areas did Abu Bakr (r.a.) had to send armies to at the same time to take care of the rebellion against Islam?",
        "optionA": "15",
        "optionB": "11",
        "optionC": "9",
        "optionD": "6",
        "answer": "11"
    }
]